Look at the slowly rotating pocket watch. Following the hypnotist's soft voice, you will find yourself in a state of deep absorption.
천천히 회전하는 회중시계를 바라봅니다. 최면술사의 부드러운 목소리를 따라가다 보면, 어느새 깊은 몰입 상태에 빠지게 됩니다.
Many people think of hypnosis as simple magic shows or bizarre tricks to control others as they please.
많은 이들이 최면을 단순한 마술쇼나 타인을 마음대로 조종하는 기이한 눈속임으로 생각하곤 합니다.
But is hypnosis really a scientific phenomenon that has actual effects on our brain and body as the public perceives?
하지만 과연 이 최면술은 대중의 인식처럼 실제로 우리 뇌와 몸에 효과가 있는 과학적 현상일까요?
The origin of hypnosis traces back to the absurd claims of Franz Anton Mesmer, an 18th-century Austrian physician.
최면의 기원은 18세기 오스트리아의 의사 프란츠 안톤 메스머의 황당한 주장으로 거슬러 올라갑니다.
He advertised that he could cure all diseases by controlling 'animal magnetism', an invisible force flowing from the universe.
그는 우주로부터 흐르는 눈에 보이지 않는 힘인 '동물 자기'를 조절해 만병을 고칠 수 있다고 선전했습니다.
However, his flashy clinic and mystical healing methods soon raised great suspicion from the French royal family.
하지만 그의 화려한 치료실과 신비주의 치료법은 곧 프랑스 왕실의 큰 의심을 사게 되었습니다.
Accordingly, the French royal family convened a committee composed of the greatest scientists of the time, led by Benjamin Franklin.
이에 따라 프랑스 왕실은 벤자민 프랭클린을 필두로 당대 최고의 과학자들로 구성된 위원회를 소집했습니다.
For the first time in scientific history, they attempted a 'blind test' by covering the patient's eyes and pretending to use real magnets.
그들은 과학사 최초로 환자의 눈을 가리고 진짜 자석인 척 속이는 '맹검 실험'을 최초로 시도했습니다.
As a result of the experiment, the body reacted only when the patient falsely believed that energy was flowing, proving animal magnetism to be a groundless scam.
실험 결과, 환자가 에너지가 흐른다고 착각했을 때만 몸이 반응했고, 동물 자기는 실체가 없는 사기로 판명났습니다.
Although it ended as a scam, this became the starting point of the 'placebo effect', where human imagination and expectation trigger bodily reactions.
비록 사기극으로 끝났지만, 이는 인간의 상상력과 기대가 몸에 반응을 일으키는 '플라시보 효과'의 시초가 되었습니다.
Later, in the 19th century, physician James Braid appeared and redefined hypnosis from a neurophysiological perspective rather than magic or religion.
그 뒤 19세기 의사 제임스 브레이드가 나타나 최면을 마법이나 종교가 아닌 신경 생리학적 관점으로 재정의했습니다.
He discovered that focusing high attention on a specific object puts the brain into a state of temporary nervous sleep and intense absorption.
그는 특정 물체에 고도로 주의를 집중하면, 뇌가 일시적인 신경성 수면과 강한 몰입 상태에 빠진다는 사실을 밝혀냈습니다.
Today, modern science has fully elucidated its working mechanism by looking inside the brain under hypnosis using fMRI devices.
오늘날 현대 과학은 fMRI 장치를 이용해 최면 상태의 뇌를 들여다봄으로써 그 작동 기전을 완벽히 규명했습니다.
Surprisingly, in a state of hypnosis, the activity of the anterior cingulate cortex, the brain region that perceives pain signals, decreases dramatically.
놀랍게도 최면 상태에서는 통증 신호를 인지하는 뇌의 전대상피질 부위 활성도가 극적으로 감소합니다.
Thanks to this, modern medicine directly utilizes hypnosis for surgery without anesthesia in patients difficult to anesthetize, or for intense psychotherapy.
덕분에 현대 의학에서는 약물 마취가 어려운 환자들의 무마취 수술이나 극심한 심리 치료에 최면을 직접 활용하고 있습니다.
Hypnosis is not a supernatural magic, but a precise and powerful tool of our mind created by human imagination and brain science.
최면은 초자연적 마법이 아닌, 인간의 상상력과 뇌 과학이 만들어내는 정교하고 강력한 우리 마음의 도구입니다.